A Register of the Lawrence Samuels collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Libertarian publications, 1961-1988.
  - Magazines
    - Libertarian Outlook, Garrison Foundation, San Francisco, California, 1985 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Libertarian Review, Libertarian Review, Inc., San Francisco, California, 1980
    - Liberty, Liberty Publishing, Port Townsend, Washington, 1991
    - Life and Liberty, New Jersey Libertarian Alliance, North Plainfield, New Jersey, 1970-1971
    - New Libertarian, New Libertarian Company of Free Traders, Costa Mesa, California, 1982-1985 (Folder 10: 4)
    - New Libertarian Notes, New York Libertarian Association, New York, 1973-1977 (Folder 10: 5)
    - New Libertarian Notes, New York Libertarian Association, New York, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Notes From the Underground, samizdat publication of the Underground Seminar on Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness, 1980 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Outlook, Libertarian Monthly, Abolitionist Association, 1972-1973
    - Scream! Individualist Anti-War Rag/Special Issue, Baltimore, Maryland, 1984
  - Newspapers
    - Arizona Liberty, the voice of the Arizona Libertarian party, 1977-1978 (Folder 11: 3)
    - Banner, Libertarian Journal, 1972-1973
    - Caliber, California Libertarian News, 1981
    - California Arena, Stanford University, 1970
    - California Political Times, Libertarian Party of California, undated
    - California Libertarian, 1980
    - California Libertarian news, 1974 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Captain America's, underground Ghetto Press, 1971
    - Carolina Renaissance, North Carolina Young Americans for Freedom, 1970
    - Cassandra, Western Pennsylvania Young Americans for Freedom, 1971
    - Challenger, published in the interest of law and order, 1967
    - Christian Laissez Faire, Institute for Human Studies, Menlo Park, California, undated
    - Colorado Liberty, Colorado Libertarian Party, 1983-1986
    - Convention News, the Tenth Anniversary Convention of the Libertarian Party, Denver, 1981
    - Counterpoint, Massachusetts Young Americans for Freedom, 1970-1971
    - Creative Californian, Young Americans for Freedom, 1970-1977 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Dimension, 1971-1972
    - Essence, Power to individual, 1972
    - Free Texas, Libertarian Party of Taxes, 1980-1983 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Free Trojan, Southern California, 1970-1971; 1984 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Free Vermont, Vermont Libertarian News, 1986
    - Freedom Reborn, 1985 National Convention of the Libertarian party, Phoenix, Arizona
    - For Real, 1971-1973
    - Future of Freedom, Conference, Long Beach City College, 1983
    - Harvard Libertarian, 1983
    - Hollywood Free Paper, 1971
    - Liberator, publication independent of the Daily Iowan, 1970
    - Libertarian Party News, Libertarian National Committee, Houston, Texas, 1982-1986 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Liberty, (Clark for President!), 1980
    - Liberty, voice of students for a libertarian society, 1982
    - Libra Freepress, 2003
    - Majority Opinion, University of Houston, Young Americans for Freedom, undated
    - Majority Speaks, independent publication, 1973
    - Movement, 1973
    - New Horizon, power to the individual, 1971 (Folder 12: 3)
    - News: Clark President, 1980
    - Outlook, commentary on the important issues of today, published by the Libertarian Party, Washington, D.C., 1977 (?)
    - Placer Gold, Libertarian Party, 1985
    - Protos, universal Banner edition, 1970-1971
    - Right-On, very unofficial University of Taxes journal of conservative opinion, 1972-1973 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Sixth Annual national Libertarian Party Convention, San Francisco, California, 1977
    - Smith's Journal, complete 1980 platform of the Libertarian Party
    - Stanford Independent, 1972
    - Stanford Libertarian, 1981
    - Starboard, Detroit, Michigan, 1970
    - Sunburst, journal of anarchist thought, published by the North American Libertarian Alliance, 1971
    - Time for Liberty, Fresno, California, 1984
    - Virginia Liberty, 1985-1986 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Write-On! Very independent Boardman student publication, 1971-1972
    - Young Libertarian, 1987
  - Newspaper clippings, 1969-1978 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Pamphlets (Folder 12: 7)
- Publications (non Libertarian), 1962-1987. (Box-folder 13: 1-4)
  Books and periodicals, newsletters and bulletins, journals, magazines and newspapers, arranged by physical form. Most of the publications are for those interested in individual liberty and the philosophy behind politics
  - Bulletins
    - American Review, Conservative Party of California, Los Angeles, 1963 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Area Bulletin, Association for Rational Environmental Alternatives, 1976
    - Bulletin, monthly report of the Economic Education and Research Forum, 1976
    - Claustrophobia, life-extension news, Portland, Oregon, 1984
    - Free Campus News Service, Washington, D.C., 1970-1973
    - Free World Chronicle, Libertarian International, Richmond, Virginia, 1985 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Freedom Guide, Sacramento, California, 1987
    - Freedom's Child Literary Journal, Freedom's Child, Grover City, California, 1982
    - Human Studies Review: A Research and Study Guide, Menlo Park, California, undated
    - Individualist, Journal of the Personal Rights Association, 1973; 1975
    - Inform, Center for Independent Education by the Cato Institute, Menlo Park, California, 1978-1981
    - Liberator, Advocates for self-Government, Inc., Fresno, California, 1986
    - Rational Individualist, Society for Rational Individualism, Silver Spring, Maryland, 1969
    - SRA Federation Bulletin, Social-Revolutionary Anarchist Federation, Mountain View, California, number 51-54, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Standard, Standard Publishing Company of Lawrence, Kansas, 1962-1963
    - Stanford Independent, 1972-1973
    - Unbound! Individualists for a Rational Society, Boston, Massachusetts, 1971-1974
    - Workers Party, for individual liberty and free enterprise, South Australian Bulletin, 1977-1978
  - Newsletters
    - Abolitionist: The American Association for the Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization, American Association for the Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization, Syracuse, New York, 1971 (Folder 14: 2)
    - All Power to the People, Open Campus Publication of California, UCLA, 1969
    - Anaheim Young Republicans Newsletter, 1971
    - Atlantis News, Atlantis Publishing Company, New York, 1970
    - Australian Economic Newsletter, Ludwig von Mises Institute, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, 1987
    - Conservative Journal, New York State Young Americans for Freedom, 1971
    - Decentralize! Non-Violent Radical Decentralist Strategy, Washington, D.C., 1987
    - Enterprise: Perspectives on the Philosophy of Business, Lundy-Fetterman School of Business, Campbell University, North Carolina, 1986
    - Familist, voice of the Familist Movement, Familist Movement, El Paso, Texas, 1986
    - Free Market, Ludwig von Mises Institute, Burlingame, California, 1986-1988
    - Free Market Reporter, Freedom Fellowship. San Francisco, California, 1977
    - Free Press Network, Free Press Association, Apple Valley, California, 1982-1985
    - International, Richmond, Virginia, 1986
    - Intellectual Activist, New York, 1980; 1989 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Liberator, Advocates for Self-Government, Inc., 1986
    - Little Guy, Citizens Strike (a non-profit organization dedicated to resistance against big government and taxation), La Mirada, California, 1979
    - Live and Let Live, Church of Eternal Life and Liberty, Inc., Southfield, Michigan, 1978
    - Movement for an Independent Pacific Channel Islands, Avalon, California, 1983
    - New Rampart, Rampart Institute, Fullerton, California, 1984-1985
    - Newsociety, 1981
    - Peaceletter, Peace Resource Center of Santa Barbara, 1983
    - Privacy News Letter, Financial Engr. Consultants, Inc., San Jose, Costa Rica
    - Quillon, Michigan Young Americans for Freedom, 1963
    - Strider Commentary, Mendocino County, California, 1985-1986
    - Superfluous Newsletter (and Memoirs), Los Angeles, California, 1985
  - Magazines
    - American Atheist, Freethought Society of America, Baltimore, Maryland, 1964 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Counterattack [publication for the self employed and small businesses], London, England, 1976-1977
    - Equitarian, conference proceedings, Equitarian Associates, Amana, Iowa, 1971
    - Freedom Today, Freedom Fellowship Church, Phoenix, Arizona, 1976-1977 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Individualist, Society for Individual Liberty, Center for Independent Education, Wichita, Kansas, 1971
    - IRI Insights, Investment Rarities, Incorporated, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1980
    - Long Life Magazine, Long Life Publishing Company, Chicago, Illinois, 1980
    - Mission Viewpoint, Church of Scientology Mission of Long Beach, California, 1978
    - New Guard, Young Americans for Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1969 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Nomos, published by Nomos Press Inc., Chicago, Illinois, 1985-1986
    - PM, students of the Cypress College evening magazine production class, 1977
    - RAP: magazine for rapport with tomorrow's people today, Pine Tree Publications, Rampart College, Santa Ana, California, 1970
    - SOL III, glossary of military obfuscations, International Fixed Calender, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1971
    - SOL III, glossary of military obfuscations, International Fixed Calender, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1971 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Under 30, Digest of the best in conservative collegiate writing, Intercollegiate Society of Individualists, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1962-1963
    - Verdict, Auric International Corporation, New York, 1964
  - Newspapers
    - Arena, Stanford's only unregulated, unauthorized, unregistered newspaper, 1970 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Aware, the square newspaper, Los Angeles, California, undated
    - Banner, Orlando, Florida, 1974
    - Deregulator, 1986
    - Disneyland War Zone: Orange County True Press, Voice of the New Right, 1970
    - Dollars and Sense, 1978
    - Eden Independent News Service, 1976
    - Flash Point, 1980
    - Free Patriot, Best of foreign and domestic advises, undated
    - Righteou's Conspiracy, Free World Publication, 1971
    - Student Voice, undated
    - Territorial Herald, Ministry of the Interior of the Royal Territorial Government of Ely-Chatelaine, Laguna Miguel, California, 1981-1987
- Books, 1978-1991. (Box 15)
  Books by Lawrence Samuels and Robert Le Fevre, 1978-1991, arranged by author
  - Robert LeFevre
    - Does Government Protection Protect? Society for Libertarian Life, edition, 1978 (?)
    - Fundamentals of Liberty, Rampart Institute, 1988
    - Nature of Man And His Government, Caxton Printers, Caldwell, Idaho, 1991
  - Lawrence Samuels, Freeland: The Search for Free/New Countries, Freeland Publishers, Fullerton, California, 1983
  - Richard Epstein, Medical Malpractice: The Case for Contract, Center for Libertarian Studies, 1979